#### **SUMMARY**

People-oriented computer science enthusiast with a couple of project experiences. Accumulated work experiences in different fields. Independent and self-motivating in learning new programming languages and concepts. Passionate in implementing current knowledge to solve problems that will stimulate growth for the company and myself.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Universiti Sains Malaysia

September 2018 - Present

Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) (Software Engineering)

Minor : Mathematics

CGPA : 3.74 (First Class Honours, as of Year 3 Semester 1)

MUET : Band 5

# TECHNICAL (IT) SKILLS

## **Programming Languages**

- C++
- Java
- Python
- SQL
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/PHP

## **Project Experiences**

- Designed, built, and documented a webpage using HTML/CSS/JavaScript/PHP.
- Planned, designed, and programmed a community-oriented application using Java in Android Studio (AS) for *Google Solutions Challenge* 2020.
- Created and documented a mock web-based database software using SQL in Oracle Application Express.
- Developed and programmed a productivity-game hybrid application using Java in AS for an assignment.
- Designed, analyzed, and prototyped mock systems using system analysis diagrams such as state diagrams, use case diagrams, and activity diagrams.

### WORK EXPERIENCES

# SellByTel Group, Virtual Demand Generation Specialist

March 2018 - July 2018

- Generated sales for Hewlett-Packard (HP) products mainly for Singapore and Malaysia market.
- Educated customers on the latest security features on HP products, especially printers.
- Consulted and advised companies on their IT setup.
- Collaborated with colleagues of different nationalities and cultures.
- Trained in computer hardware knowledge and soft skills.
- Communicated in multiple languages daily with Singaporean and Malaysian customers.

### United Business Media, PR Contract Staff

**January 2018 - March 2018** 

- Participated in organizing the Malaysian International Furniture Fair (MIFF) 2018.
- Contacted embassies and companies regarding invitations and sponsorships.
- Adapted and supported my supervisor throughout the tedious workflow and constant changes.
- Collaborated with multiple departments to ensure a smooth progress.
- Led and supervised a group of temp staffs during MIFF 2018.

## INVOLVEMENTS/ ACHIEVEMENTS

- National Top 10 for ASEAN Data Science Explorer (ADSE) 2020.
- Organizing Committee Marketing for Fall National Induction Leadership Conference 2019.
- Organizing Committee Publicity for International-Penang Pesta Hoki 2018.
- Organizing Committee Arbiter for USM Chess Open Tournament International 2019.
- Project director for various events under USM Bridge and Chess Club.

### **CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

### USM Bridge and Chess Club, Member

**September 2018 - June 2020** 

- Organized numerous events in USM to ensure positive cashflow for the club.
- Adapted self to skillsets such as poster design and photography for club events.
- Participated in organizing the International Chess Open Tournament, which is the hallmark of the club.

# AIESEC, Member (iGV)

**September 2018 - June 2019** 

- Interviewed potential volunteers from across the globe and determine volunteers who are fit to volunteer in Penang for *Project Speak Up*.
- Facilitated the global volunteers during their stay in Penang.
- Collaborated with other departments to ensure the growth of AIESEC in Penang.

### SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Microsoft Visio, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Dev-C++, SAP Analytics, Adobe XD. Beginner in Adobe Illustrator and Premiere Pro.

### LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Trilingual in English, Chinese & Malay. Beginner in Japanese and Korean.

#### **OTHERS**

GitHub : DanielChang98 Code Forces : danielchang98